[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a147", "question": "Who sang the title song to the 1964 James Bond film \"Goldfinger\"?", "answer": "Shirley Bassey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf2", "question": "What year did actor Heath Ledger die?", "answer": "2008", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ed", "question": "What was the call sign of Tom Cruise's fighter pilot character in the movie \"Top Gun\"?", "answer": "Maverick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb5", "question": "Which type of nonsensical humorous verse was popularized by Edward Lear?", "answer": "Limerick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ba", "question": "Why is Oneida Lake sometimes called \"the thumb\"?", "answer": "It sites beside the Finger Lakes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338abf", "question": "Margaret Munnerlyn Mitchell, author of the book \"Gone with the Wind\", was born in what city?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad30", "question": "What US president endorsed the Louisiana Purchase in 1803?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a632", "question": "The Niagara Falls empties in which Great Lake?", "answer": "Lake Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339329", "question": "In \"The Godfather\", who plays Michael Corleone?", "answer": "Al Pacino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3c1bc4f032c0db195b478", "question": "What tribe of Native Americans was the first to encounter the Pilgrims?", "answer": "The Wampanoag", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea42f7ff048f679a45ab7e", "question": "What is the sea parrot commonly known as?", "answer": "Puffin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7df", "question": "What are the bumps on the tongue that carry the taste buds called?", "answer": "Papillae", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e8a8b02404ad935a7e1a644", "question": "What is the BTS Variety Show called on their V-LIVE channel?", "answer": "Run BTS", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c827", "question": "The Egyptian plover is a bird best known for its symbiotic relationship with what host animal?", "answer": "The crocodile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd01", "question": "What can be taken \"en passant\"?", "answer": "Pawns in chess", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdfbefc003d27d341092bd3", "question": "How many Brazilian states are there?", "answer": "26", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e971c7ccba3ffe45786f9", "question": "Melissophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Bees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac3b", "question": "What Egyptian city was founded by Alexander the Great in 331 BC?", "answer": "Alexandria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be7f", "question": "Ronald Reagan made headlines in 1980 for claiming that 80 percent of air pollution comes from what?", "answer": "Trees", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be0", "question": "Who wrote the Booker prize winning novel \"The Bone People\"?", "answer": "Kerry Hulme", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397dd", "question": "Which Hollywood Actor was born Issur Danielovitch in 1918?", "answer": "Kirk Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59d", "question": "What word denotes the energy an object has because it is in motion?", "answer": "Kinetic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af9c", "question": "New Mexico, California and which other state did the US gain after the Mexican War?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad0", "question": "The Luxor Hotel & Casino in Las Vegas was built in what unusual shape?", "answer": "A pyramid", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a99e", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Lamington\"?", "answer": "Papua New Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3bd", "question": "In which country did the Boxer Rebellion take place?", "answer": "China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b631", "question": "In NATO's phonetic alphabet, what is the letter \"A\" referred to as?", "answer": "Alpha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9377e6bd93ce3a4e5f66e", "question": "Dendrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Trees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601214f563c99d48cd169ae4", "question": "Which researcher corrected Einstein's theory of a static universe?", "answer": "Edwin Hubble -- He concluded that the universe is actually expanding, something Einstein would admit was his own blunder.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3af5ff048f679a45ab30", "question": "What are the three-time periods of the dinosaurs?", "answer": "Triassic, Jurassic, and Cretaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f6fb1a9e54d890926f6d2", "question": "Which country is home to the colorful Rainbow Mountain?", "answer": "Peru -- AKA Vinicunca, it achieves its vibrant hues thanks to natural weathering, which has exposed mineral strips in the earth.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a8f", "question": "What does \"J.R.R.\" stand for in J.R.R. Tolkien's name?", "answer": "John Ronald Reuel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600240464be4723ccac22163", "question": "What is the name of the protagonist CIA analyst in Tom Clancy's novels?", "answer": "Jack Ryan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded0d5ea2747c8aff16d2d", "question": "Which country's wine might be labelled \"AOC\"?", "answer": "France's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea82a5ff048f679a45ac22", "question": "Where is human skin thinnest?", "answer": "Eyelids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fc25240865c716bd8505f24", "question": "Who said, \"Buy more land, they aren't making it anymore.\"?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a3", "question": "What mountain chain extends from western Canada down through Northern California?", "answer": "The Cascades", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c606", "question": "Which planet is named after the God of the Sky?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e19", "question": "In what 1979 novel is the \"Thumb\" device actually a Sub-Etha Sens-O-Matic?", "answer": "The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5cefc199948005ec986edce6", "question": "What powers Iron Man's suit?", "answer": "Arc reactor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c5", "question": "What year marked the publishing of Bram Stoker's novel \"Dracula\"?", "answer": "1897", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f87", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Dreamgirls\"?", "answer": "Jennifer Hudson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133910a", "question": "What year was Viktor Frankl's book \"Man's Search for Meaning\" published?", "answer": "1946", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca72", "question": "What is measured in fathoms?", "answer": "Depth of water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ec22838dc25ca9e12ef627", "question": "In which city can you find the famed Arch of Hadrian?", "answer": "Ahtens, Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5e", "question": "What rocker's first album was named \"Greetings from Asbury Park, NJ\"?", "answer": "Bruce Springsteen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c5", "question": "What are the three main sections of an insect's body?", "answer": "The head, the abdomen and the thorax", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3fd", "question": "The gopher is a member of what order of mammals?", "answer": "Rodents", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c746", "question": "What is the largest living bird on Earth?", "answer": "The ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59db76db0ab2c8f322317fe8", "question": "In which ocean would you find the Republic of Seychelles?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71b", "question": "What do South Africans decorate at Christmas time with cotton, wool and tinsel?", "answer": "Their windows", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd8236cd0de9af39e9d46af", "question": "Which US First Lady was the first to give birth in the White House?", "answer": "Frances Cleveland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a937", "question": "What is the only nation that shares a land border with San Marino?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69a5e20565ad31a57c753", "question": "In which year of the 1900's did the Japanese army invade Manchuria?", "answer": "1931", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b1", "question": "The port city of Sheboygan is located in which US state?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d2", "question": "Who is the Roman goddess of hunting?", "answer": "Diana", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc1", "question": "Who had a best seller at age 84 with her autobiography \"Me: Stories of My Life\"?", "answer": "Katharine Hepburn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d75", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Parish Boy's Progress\"?", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c3", "question": "In what year did Martin Luther King Jr. deliver his \"I Have a  Dream\" speech?", "answer": "1963", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d9b", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Marvolo Riddle?", "answer": "J. K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c283", "question": "How often are brain cells replaced?", "answer": "Never", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d2", "question": "What did Harry Houdini die from on Halloween in 1926?", "answer": "Ruptured appendix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd70", "question": "What was the answer to the trivia question in the very first \"Got Milk\" ad, in 1993?", "answer": "Aaron Burr", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7be6a2b316f4693fb6790", "question": "Sweet potatoes are commonly but mistakenly sold under what name?", "answer": "Yams (However, real yams are a completely different vegetable, with a brown bark-like skin and a starchy flavor.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bffe", "question": "In popular culture, what is a \"Tamagotchi\"?", "answer": "Virtual pet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a266", "question": "Which dance classic did the group \"The Trammps\" bring us?", "answer": "Disco Inferno", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45f", "question": "Who received a patent for the first electric razor in 1930?", "answer": "Jacob Schick", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe378ce0ada16518afdc054", "question": "Which popular Christmas song was originally written for a Broadway musical?", "answer": "\"White Christmas\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339395", "question": "Which actor from the cast of the movie \"Rain Man\" won an Oscar?", "answer": "Dustin Hoffmann", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d06", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Pedro Sanchez?", "answer": "Napoleon Dynamite", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b9", "question": "What instrument did Don Henley play as a member of Eagles?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339009", "question": "What is the more common name for serigraphy?", "answer": "Screen printing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe93aaf6bd93ce3a4e5f699", "question": "What science combines computer science, statistics, engineering, and biology?", "answer": "Bioinformatics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f93", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Sayonara\"?", "answer": "Miyoshi Umeki", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888e", "question": "What is Dennis the Menace's last name?", "answer": "Mitchell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909d246bb53d1af65886507", "question": "Which star is represented by placing a star on top of a Christmas tree?", "answer": "Star of Bethlehem", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d7", "question": "Humbert Humbert is a character in which popular novel?", "answer": "Lolita", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ab99c6121a8909e5c332d35", "question": "Which band released the album \"Breakfast in America\"?", "answer": "Supertramp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc9", "question": "Who was sent to the electric chair on the testimony of her brother David Greenglass?", "answer": "Ethel Rosenberg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a32d", "question": "What year was the sequel to the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\" released?", "answer": "1990", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596dfcfa9616e6c6d4eba4f3", "question": "What year did the video game Grand Theft Auto V come out?", "answer": "2013", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab7a", "question": "What year did Mauritius gain its independence from Britain?", "answer": "1968", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b42", "question": "In what movie did Tom Cruise play real-life character Ron Kovic?", "answer": "Born on the 4 th of July", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f1781e4b8195c09b948d5c2", "question": "Which abolitionist wrote the newspapers called \"The Liberator\"?", "answer": "William Lloyd Garrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a71c", "question": "Which US state shares a border with Ohio, Indiana and Wisconsin?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6fa", "question": "Somnoplasty is a cosmetic procedure designed to help with what?", "answer": "Snoring", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56c", "question": "Phobos is the name of one of the moons of which planet?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c37a4815febcc896f9272", "question": "What Turkish city has spread to both sides of the Bosphorus Strait?", "answer": "Istanbul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339597", "question": "Musical duo Kaoma introduced the world to which dance in 1989?", "answer": "Lambada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53d", "question": "What does the word \"honcho\" mean in Japanese?", "answer": "Squad Leader", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cefc19f948005ec986edce7", "question": "What powers Iron Man's suit?", "answer": "Arc reactor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad5", "question": "What year did Andy Warhol die?", "answer": "1987", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05f", "question": "What famous Cherokee Indian created the alphabet for the Cherokee language?", "answer": "Sequoyah", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1b", "question": "Filbert is an alternative name for which nut?", "answer": "Hazelnut", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb57de5dad637d903c880c", "question": "What is the name of the oldest bridge in Venice, which crosses the city's famous Grand Canal?", "answer": "The Ponte di Rialto, or Rialto Bridge, was built between 1588 and 1591 to span the width of the Grand Canal.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0a", "question": "What year did Anna Nicole Smith die from a drug overdose?", "answer": "2007", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c702", "question": "What planet is named for the Roman equivalent of the Greek god Zeus?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bef4", "question": "What is the fear of parents-in-law known as?", "answer": "Soceraphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c563", "question": "What name is given to a triangle with all equal sides?", "answer": "Equilateral", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f191ff048f679a45aab2", "question": "Is it the female or the male turkey that gobbles?", "answer": "The male gobbles and the female cackles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ff", "question": "What city is the capital of Djibouti?", "answer": "Djibouti City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c40", "question": "Who wrote the famous poem \"The Waste Land\"?", "answer": "T.S. Elliot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd72", "question": "What is sinology the study of?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399bf", "question": "What was Captain Stubing's first name, on the TV show \"The Love Boat\"?", "answer": "Merrill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389be", "question": "What country provides the setting for \"The King and I\"?", "answer": "Siam (Thailand)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f1", "question": "Who were the founders of the Sony Corporation?", "answer": "Masaru Ibuka and Akio Morita", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf9", "question": "What was the first nonoriginal color of cereal pieces added to Trix in 1980?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f30501dd7bf43be5e813", "question": "What does TCBY stand for?", "answer": "The Country's Best Yogurt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e94d21b5ea27d7a1303aed8", "question": "What two players were selected before Michael Jordan in the 1984 NBA Draft?", "answer": "Akeem Olajuwon and Sam Bowie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339648", "question": "What was the nickname of Gene Hackman's character in The French Connection?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d5", "question": "In 1991, who finally broke Bob Beamon's decades-old long jump record?", "answer": "Mike Powell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a728cdf6bcd28c11938328d", "question": "What was used for blood in Hitchcock's \"Psycho\"?", "answer": "Chocolate syrup", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f31aff048f679a45aabd", "question": "What is the most volcanically active body in our solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter's moon Io", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e9", "question": "What ape's name is Malay for \"old man of the forest\"?", "answer": "The orangutan's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601219cf63c99d48cd169afb", "question": "What is someone who shoes horses?", "answer": "A farrier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad37", "question": "Who was the 42nd President of the United States?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59675c4d2b59efe0e9417e94", "question": "What was Vince Gill\u2019s last #1 as a solo recording artist?", "answer": "Tryin\u2019 To Get over You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c976", "question": "What does an ombrometer measure?", "answer": "Rainfall", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dcf", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"chutzpah\"?", "answer": "Yiddish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f4e8ff048f679a45aacd", "question": "Megalophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Large things or objects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb80", "question": "Which one of tennis' Grand Slam tournaments did Pete Sampras never win?", "answer": "French Open", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339978", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", where was Lenny born?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8af1901dd7bf43be5e787", "question": "What causes the holes in Swiss cheese?", "answer": "Bacteria", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03d", "question": "In 1969, what woman said \"No woman, in my time, will ever be Prime Minister\"?", "answer": "Margaret Thatcher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c571fbde8045e48466ac", "question": "What is the universal solvent?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e8f7fe83fe1f2a824be2", "question": "Which monarch appointed Pitt the Younger to the office of prime minister in December 1783?", "answer": "George III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c9df877e98cb977789fd", "question": "Which European city is known as Auld Reekie?", "answer": "Edinburgh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5da855f01aec824685d88d04", "question": "What is the most common street name in the United States?", "answer": "Park, according to a Washington Post study", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2cf712596a59cbdfbd36f", "question": "Potassium Nitrate is also known as what?", "answer": "Saltpeter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594125b6bab1e6f9796f1b56", "question": "What two colors are on the flag of Israel?", "answer": "Blue and white", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e73", "question": "What superteam includes Angel, Beast, Cyclops, Iceman and Marvel Girl?", "answer": "The X-Men", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbb", "question": "What novelist of westerns went by his middle name, since his first was Pearl?", "answer": "Zane Grey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdee", "question": "The ruby anniversary celebrates how many years of marriage?", "answer": "Forty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f8", "question": "Into what body of water does the Danube River empty?", "answer": "The Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b14b", "question": "What typewriter key was introduced by Remington in 1878, ending the need for two keys for each letter?", "answer": "Shift key", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba96", "question": "The pasta shape called \"farfalle\" gets its name from the Italian word for what insect?", "answer": "Butterfly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae03", "question": "In which war was the Charge of the Light Brigade?", "answer": "Crimean", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc64", "question": "How many different car models were there in the first Hot Wheels release in 1968?", "answer": "16", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c96ffbde8045e48466ec", "question": "Which farm animal was the first-ever mammal to be cloned?", "answer": "Sheep -- In 1996, Dolly the sheep was the first-ever mammal to be cloned using a somatic cell. She was named after Dolly Parton.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b20f", "question": "Who was assassinated by Leon Czolgosz?", "answer": "William McKinley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f3", "question": "What is the name the Australian film based on the life of pianist David Helfgott?", "answer": "Shine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6b502fb6c85e9e634ff45", "question": "Where is the \"Land of 10,000 Lakes\"?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ac", "question": "Which Kingdom is Greenland a part of?", "answer": "The Kingdom of Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339312", "question": "In the diner scene from the movie \"When Harry Met Sally\", what did Meg Ryan order?", "answer": "Chef salad and apple pie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133907d", "question": "What controversial book did Germaine Greer write?", "answer": "The Female Eunuch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae6d", "question": "What did the class entering Harvard in the fall of 1967 have for the first time?", "answer": "Women", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15e", "question": "What year was Mother Teresa born?", "answer": "1910", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6bac8fb6c85e9e634ff52", "question": "What is the name for the group of men who elect a Pope?", "answer": "College of Cardinals", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b58", "question": "What Broadway Musical is based off the opera \"La Bohem\"?", "answer": "Rent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca1", "question": "Who was the principal of Riverdale High School in the \"Archie\" comics?", "answer": "Mr. Weatherbee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e17bfe83fe1f2a824b94", "question": "What major mistake did the Allies make in preparing to defend against Germany\u2019s attack on France?", "answer": "They misinterpreted where the main invasion would take place", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be6b", "question": "What is Dodger Stadium also known as?", "answer": "Chavez Ravine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c1", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Wolverine State\"?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abae", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Maryland?", "answer": "Annapolis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b774", "question": "Brigham Young was a leader of which religious group?", "answer": "Mormons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5977432a284458f1d7854427", "question": "Albert Einstein was offered the position of prime minister of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e6b653fb6c85e9e634ff48", "question": "The fear of men is known as what?", "answer": "Androphobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c4", "question": "Who wielded a sword named Excalibur?", "answer": "King Arthur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b5", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Pakistan and Bangladesh?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae79", "question": "Which Confederate general surrender at Appomattox Court House?", "answer": "General Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e7e0b24f84e0b9f9ffc0", "question": "Which state surrounds the Australian Capital Territory?", "answer": "New South Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a977", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Rajya Sabha?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5a", "question": "What was the name of the town where all the characters lived in the comic strip \u201cL\u2019il Abner\u201d?", "answer": "Dogpatch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec88ebec223966ae8f8825", "question": "Prison Warden, Norton, in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\" believes in two things. What are they?", "answer": "Discipline and the Lord", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd809e347d002c297e4c6", "question": "In Greek mythology, who flew too close to the Sun?", "answer": "Icarus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973f", "question": "Which Disney film included the songs \"Chim Chim Cheree\" and \"Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious\"?", "answer": "Mary Poppins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69ae020565ad31a57c757", "question": "What was the first non-axis jet plane to see combat?", "answer": "Gloster Meteor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590721263745b36be73039f5", "question": "Who played the role of Kris Kringle in the 1947 film \"Miracle on 34th Street\"?", "answer": "Edmund Gwenn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdabadc0b8cce1e6fda7058", "question": "Which country does the chorizo sausage originate from?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec261b8dc25ca9e12ef646", "question": "Which country traditionally gives London's Trafalgar Square its Christmas tree?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede6216ce05a3942286df6", "question": "Who is the host of the Travel Channel's culinary adventure show \"No Reservations\"?", "answer": "Anthony Bourdain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5954e76b8e82ccaf3b9a67ba", "question": "What do male lions do about 20 hours a day?", "answer": "Sleep", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a22d", "question": "Who played the title role in the film \"Mad Max\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a9a", "question": "What was Bob Dylan's first Top 10 hit?", "answer": "Like a Rolling Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d06e21a1c922dd1ac64b1", "question": "Pont Neuf is the oldest bridge over the river Seine, located in which French city?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339090", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was the god of the underworld?", "answer": "Hades", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f71efa9e54d890926f6e7", "question": "What was the original name of Austin, the capital of Texas?", "answer": "Waterloo -- It was renamed after Texas leader Stephen F. Austin in 1839.  It became the state capital in 1845.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa2", "question": "What musical won the Tony Award for Best Musical in 1996?", "answer": "Rent", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ec23f08dc25ca9e12ef634", "question": "In \"Gulliver's Travels\", what is the name of the flying island?", "answer": "Laputa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc5cbec223966ae8f8883", "question": "Bruce Willis played a convict turned time traveler in what 1995 movie?", "answer": "\"12 Monkeys\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d7322596a59cbdfbd3b3", "question": "What did Nestle pay to obtain the original chocolate chip cookie recipe?", "answer": "A lifetime supply of chocolate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea45cdff048f679a45ab99", "question": "If nitrous oxide is added to an engine, what will the effect be?", "answer": "Adds more oxygen to the engine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b6992cbe762b54eb9be9426", "question": "What country has the calling code +20?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba6", "question": "What Wyoming National Monument is featured in the movie \"Close Encounters of the Third Kind\"?", "answer": "Devil's Tower", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c3", "question": "The world's least salty seawater is found in the Gulf of Bothnia, between what two countries?", "answer": "Sweden and Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9ba95364247bf200fb899", "question": "Necrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Death or dead bodies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad36", "question": "When first founded by Benjamin Franklin, what was the job of the \"bucket brigade\"?", "answer": "To put out fires", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7ff9b93a3a814d89068c56", "question": "What word describes one tenth of a nautical mile?", "answer": "Cable", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb5d285dad637d903c8822", "question": "What is Valentine's Day called in Brazil?", "answer": "Dia dos Namorados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab963586faa38a764be51c", "question": "What was the original cost of the first Ford Model T, sold in 1909?", "answer": "$825", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d07", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Garth Algar?", "answer": "Wayne Campbell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76d", "question": "Who created the icy treat better known as \"popsicle\"?", "answer": "Frank Epperson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339413", "question": "In the opening scene of the credits for \"The Brady Brunch\", which of the females appears in the upper corner?", "answer": "Marcia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946e", "question": "Who played the role of Daisy Randone in the 1999 movie \"Girl, Interrupted\"?", "answer": "Brittany Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c830", "question": "What hinged surfaces on a plane's wingtips allow the aircraft to roll?", "answer": "Ailerons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f507ff048f679a45aad0", "question": "Necrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Death and dead things", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b423", "question": "In what year did Konrad Adenauer become the first Chancellor of West Germany?", "answer": "1949", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade1", "question": "What year did the Han Dynasty come into power?", "answer": "206 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc39", "question": "What do the initials in O.J. Simpson's name stand for?", "answer": "Orenthal James", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339398", "question": "Who directed the movie \"The Pianist\"?", "answer": "Roman Polanski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c36ca815febcc896f926a", "question": "What drug is obtained from the cinchona tree?", "answer": "Quinine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a329", "question": "Who played the role of Elaine in the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Annette O'Toole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071e5d3745b36be73039e2", "question": "Which comic book publisher publishes the \"Revival\" series?", "answer": "Image Comics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87a", "question": "The first atomic bomb test split an atom of what fissionable element?", "answer": "Plutonium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8c", "question": "Who was engaged to magician David Copperfield for six years in the 1990's?", "answer": "Claudia Schiffer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c3", "question": "How many labours did Hercules perform to free himself from bondage?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21c", "question": "What city was Wild Bill Hickok killed in?", "answer": "Deadwood", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b088", "question": "What year was the Hubble telescope launched into orbit?", "answer": "1990", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b655", "question": "The entrance to what New York City landmark has a pair of lion sculptures?", "answer": "Public Library", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ecd808d98002fdd633c1", "question": "What is an Ishihara Test used for?", "answer": "To check colour blindness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eb0", "question": "What cartoonist created the bearded guru named Mr. Natural?", "answer": "R. Crumb", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a869", "question": "Andorra is landlocked by what two countries?", "answer": "France and Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5904a4c7cf93664eb10486c6", "question": "Shortly after meeting David, which North American city did Katchoo disappear to for 2 months, in the comic series \"Strangers in Paradise\"?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396cd", "question": "Who is Freakazoid?", "answer": "Dexter Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339451", "question": "Who plays the role of Captain Jack Aubrey in the movie \"Master and Commander\"?", "answer": "Russell Crowe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b6", "question": "What does a \"caliber\" measure?", "answer": "The approximate internal diameter of a gun barrel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cf01877e98cb97778a49", "question": "Where is the \"Cathedral of Rum\"?", "answer": "Puerto Rico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09d", "question": "What wine barrel contains 252 gallons?", "answer": "Tun", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b4e", "question": "The 1999 Russell Crowe film \"The Insider\" concerned a whistle-blower in what industry?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b85", "question": "What\u2019s the ballet term for a 360 degree turn on one foot?", "answer": "A Pirouette", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad7", "question": "What is the Christmas Carol \"O Christmas Tree\" known as in German?", "answer": "O Tannenbaum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac4", "question": "What early rock pioneer once told an unresponsive audience, \"I hope you all get heart attacks\"?", "answer": "Jerry Lee Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339caf", "question": "What breed of dog is McGruff?", "answer": "Bloodhound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b37701dd7bf43be5e7b0", "question": "A kindle is a group of what animals?", "answer": "Kittens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc2d", "question": "What is Barbie's full name?", "answer": "Barbara Millicent Roberts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c913", "question": "The amount of what substance in granite determines its color?", "answer": "Feldspar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb69765dad637d903c8848", "question": "In which U.S. state can you find a river nicknamed the \"River of No Return\"?", "answer": "Idaho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398bd", "question": "Who was the final act at Woodstock?", "answer": "Jimi Hendrix", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f51", "question": "\"Girls with a Pearl Earring\" is one of only thirty-five extant works of what Dutch painter?", "answer": "Jan Vermeer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b169", "question": "What was the name of the site used to build the Empire State Building?", "answer": "John Thompson Farm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067b82ff9c0647b50a8065", "question": "What 2009 first-person shooter game mostly takes place in 2016?", "answer": "Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c028d0aea32143fcb1d3b55", "question": "In music, what is the term to gradually decrease in volume?", "answer": "Decrescendo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b548", "question": "What day is hump day?", "answer": "Wednesday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600a274ee958e8c9f3127314", "question": "Who is the city of Regina, Saskatchewan named for?", "answer": "Queen Victoria - Originally a hunters\u2019 camp named Pile O\u2019Bones, the settlement was renamed Regina, Latin for \"queen\".", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c71b", "question": "What word describes a horse with a golden coat and a white or silver mane and tail?", "answer": "Palomino", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b668", "question": "What is the length-to-width ratio of a regulation pool table?", "answer": "2:1", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afa", "question": "The movies \"Black Hawk Down\", \"Blade Runner\", and \"Gladiator\" were all directed by whom?", "answer": "Ridley Scott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa2d", "question": "What's the capital of Comoros?", "answer": "Moroni", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ba", "question": "Which US state is directly south of Georgia?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1e", "question": "What country celebrates its National Day on 14th July?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e80685de59ea584496feb2", "question": "In which US city would you find the Space Needle?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0d", "question": "What novel won Alice Walker a Pulitzer Prize in 1983?", "answer": "The Color Purple", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef657b6ce05a3942286e6d", "question": "Where is the oldest annual horse race?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8cc0ec223966ae8f884e", "question": "What movie inspired the director of \"The Shawshank Redemption\" into using a voice-over narration.", "answer": "\"Goodfellas\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee9", "question": "In \"Uncle Tom's Cabin\", Eliza's famous flight across the ice floes takes place on what frozen river?", "answer": "The Ohio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a80c", "question": "What sea is located directly north of Poland?", "answer": "Baltic Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b1743d1bb2d29f81593b6f6", "question": "What can you find on California's Mount Lee?", "answer": "The \"Hollywood\" sign", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e7", "question": "Everglades National Park is located in which US state?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f3f101dd7bf43be5e81b", "question": "SNAP stands for what in the US?", "answer": "Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ab", "question": "Tornadoes are columns of air that generally come into contact with what kind of clouds?", "answer": "Cumulonimbus cloud", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ff", "question": "What do the bar code letters UPC stand for?", "answer": "Universal Product Code", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff666ab52a821ff76ae8afa", "question": "Which labor standard were the striking workers out to achieve which eventually led to the Haymarket Affair in the US?", "answer": "8-Hour Work Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3db3ff048f679a45ab50", "question": "Something that is toward the end or away from the center of the body can also be called what?", "answer": "Distal", "category": "science"}]